<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>admin &#8211; Be True</title>
	<atom:link href="http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/author/admin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php</link>
	<description>Thank you for reading fresh news</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 10:50:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The country building a ‘new London’ every year</title>
		<link>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/2020/04/21/uefa-recommended-to-finish-the-national-championships-and-cups/</link>
					<comments>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/2020/04/21/uefa-recommended-to-finish-the-national-championships-and-cups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Без рубрики]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://l91tr.yilorp.space/?p=41</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With half of the world’s new buildings to be constructed in China – how can it build them better? I In the north of Beijing, not far from the “Bird’s Nest” National Stadium, a four-storey orange building hums quietly. It doesn’t look too different from the other buildings on the campus of China Academy of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With half of the world’s new buildings to be constructed in China – how can it build them better?<br />
I<br />
In the north of Beijing, not far from the “Bird’s Nest” National Stadium, a four-storey orange building hums quietly. It doesn’t look too different from the other buildings on the campus of China Academy of Building Research, or from the millions that rise up every year in China. Yet, it is running on only one-fifth of the total energy used by similar office buildings in the capital city.</p>
<p>The building is part of a movement to make China’s buildings more sustainable. By some estimates, almost half of the world’s construction will take place in China in the coming decade. The country already builds two billion sq m of new floorspace each year – if laid out over a single storey, that would cover 1.3 times the size of the entire footprint of London. It’s an extraordinary figure, especially when you consider that worldwide, the buildings and construction sector accounts for around 39% of carbon dioxide emissions released from energy use and industry.</p>
<p>Over the years, China’s rapid economic growth has significantly increased buildings’ energy use and posed a significant challenge for the environment. From 2001 to 2016, the primary energy consumption in China’s building sector more than doubled, reaching the equivalent of just under a billion tonnes of coal. And the carbon cost of constructing buildings in the first place, including the raw materials and energy used throughout the supply chain, makes up around a fifth of China’s carbon emissions.</p>
<p>“What China needs to do is to ensure people’s life quality continues to improve but not at the expense of a speedy rise in buildings’ energy consumption,” says Zhu Yingxin of Tsinghua University, a researcher who has developed green architecture standards in China.</p>
<p>How can China go about this enormous task?</p>
<p>You might also like:</p>
<p>Which trees reduce air pollution best<br />
The remarkable power of the prickly pear<br />
The long road to a zero-carbon country<br />
One of the most visible ways that architecture is becoming greener in China is the most literal one – through vegetation-rich tree-covered buildings.</p>
<p>Italian architect Stefano Boeri has been a pioneer of the vertical forest. Since debuting the Bosco Verticale, a pair of verdant high-end residential buildings in Milan, Boeri and colleagues have turned to China for their next vertical forest, to be built in Nanjing, the capital of Jiangsu province in the East of the country. </p>
<p>Planting trees in cities would be helpful to counter the new high-rises’ CO2 emissions, as well as reducing urban air pollution. But, in China’s dense urban areas where space is often at a high premium, the appeal of creating forests that spread upwards, not outwards, is becoming an increasingly attractive option.</p>
<p>Building greenery into high-rises maximises the opportunity for forests in urban areas where space is at a premium (Credit: Stefano Boeri Architetti)<br />
Building greenery into high-rises maximises the opportunity for forests in urban areas where space is at a premium (Credit: Stefano Boeri Architetti)</p>
<p>Nanjing’s two green towers were set to complete in late 2020, but the project has been delayed by the pandemic. The buildings will harbour 2,500 shrubs and more than 1,000 trees on their facades. Right now, some 600 trees from local species, such as Chinese photinia, cherry trees and ginkgo, are growing in a suburban nursery, destined for the towers’ walls. They will be grown to a height of six to nine metres, before they are ready to be taken to the site.</p>
<p>Yibo Xu, who is a partner at Stefano Boeri Architetti and leads its Shanghai office, explains that the trees will go through wind-tunnel experiments to test their strength before workers install them on the towers’ terraces and balconies, where they will improve the microclimate and biodiversity. The experiments simulate the winds the trees might face at different heights of the building, to make sure trees are put at a safe height for their size, lowering the risk of them falling down during storms.</p>
<p>Cement alone releases 8% of the world’s global carbon emissions each year<br />
Many provinces in China have introduced policies that encourage making greenery an integral part of high-rises. In Zhejiang province, for example, a building with “sky garden balconies” can exempt these green spaces from its total floor area when calculating the plot ratio. This ratio is a building’s gross floor area (of all floors) to the size of the plot that the building sits on. Lower plot ratios mean more livable environments, and so the property can be sold for a higher price. It’s quite a practical incentive, Xu says.</p>
<p>But to get the full effect, you can’t just add vegetation to a building here and there, notes Malaysian eco-architect Ken Yeang. Instead, greening a building requires careful planning, to make sure that the trees are well connected with others of their species nearby, to ensure a continuous habitat that benefits animals, birds and insects.</p>
<p>Although green buildings like this require a great deal of planning, to the architects, it’s worth it. “We have many tools nowadays if we want to reduce the production of CO2,” Boeri says. “But we only have one way to absorb the CO2 already produced.” That’s drawing carbon down from the atmosphere and storing it in another form – the most efficient mechanism for which is vegetation.</p>
<p>It’s an admirable sentiment; but the vertical forests in Nanjing are expected to absorb just 25 tonnes of CO2 every year – about the same as 10 round-trip flights from Beijing to London. But even if vertical forests become widespread, it will take a lot more to make a dent in the carbon emissions of China’s construction industry.</p>
<p>The 3D-printing construction company WinSun uses recycled materials in the &#8220;ink&#8221; to print its structures (Credit: Winsun)<br />
The 3D-printing construction company WinSun uses recycled materials in the &#8220;ink&#8221; to print its structures (Credit: Winsun)</p>
<p>Making vegetation a part of ordinary high-rises is a very visible way to “green” them, but improving their construction and building materials could have a much greater impact in terms of carbon. Cement alone releases 8% of the world’s global carbon emissions each year. By one estimate, in 2015 China’s carbon emissions from building materials – including steel, cement, iron and aluminum – and construction combined was equivalent to burning one billion tonnes of coal (for context, in 2018, China burnt 3.83 billion tonnes of coal).</p>
<p>Sourced from places like steel mills, coal plants and urban construction sites, solid wastes are sorted, granulated and processed into the ink that feeds the 3D printer<br />
One way to get this figure down is to use recycled construction materials. About 170 miles (270km) away down the Yangtze River, which flows from Nanjing to Shanghai, a company called WinSun has been turning recyclable materials into a cluster of 3D-printed buildings, claimed to be the largest of its kind.</p>
<p>WinSun is the brainchild of Ma Yihe, a mechanical engineer turned entrepreneur. With Ma’s 3D-printing technology, only nine workers are needed to work on the seven buildings in that cluster – a job that would traditionally take a 200-people team. Tonnes of wood panels are saved too, because a 3D printer has no need for scaffolds.</p>
<p>At the center of this cluster of buildings is WinSun’s sustainable 3D printing “ink”. Sourced from places like steel mills, coal plants and urban construction sites, various solid wastes are sorted, granulated and processed into the ink that feeds the 3D printer. This substance is not entirely second-hand though, as it also requires a certain amount of desert sand, as conventional concrete does. The steel mill wastes are the easiest to process, Ma says, and can be used for up to 60% of the building ink.</p>
<p>From recycle to reuse</p>
<p>Better still than grinding down waste materials to create a new building is to repurpose one that already exists.</p>
<p>In China’s Xiong’an New Area, about 60 miles (100km) south-west of Beijing, a deserted clothing factory has been repurposed into an office building. Liu Heng, director of the Green Architecture Design and Research Institute, is the architect behind the project. He kept the major structures of the old factory, created new floor surfaces with pieces of old glass, and used chunks of old cement from the building to build walls in the yard outside.</p>
<p>The emissions from construction, including use of raw materials, was equivalent to burning one billion tonnes of coal in 2015 (Credit: Reuters)<br />
The emissions from construction, including use of raw materials, was equivalent to burning one billion tonnes of coal in 2015 (Credit: Reuters)</p>
<p>The most important renovations were for energy efficiency; for example, Liu installed a “curtain wall” to form an all-around corridor where the air in that space reduces heat exchange between the outside environment and the main office. A staff member working in the center once told a TV reporter that in one winter the building stayed around 18C without heating. The coldest month in Beijing has an average temperature of -3C.</p>
<p>Liu agrees with Ma that 3D printing would allow a better future for architecture, because of its speed, its need for fewer laborers, and its potential to minimise construction waste. “If they use certain materials to enhance the 3D printed house’s insulation properties, that would be even better,” he adds.</p>
<p>Finding ways to use of the structure and design of a building to heat or cool it without mechanical means – known as passive design – is something that Beijing-based architect Dong Mei has been exploring for almost 20 years. One of her major projects was to design a teaching building for Peking University in Beijing in 2005 – the year that China issued its first guideline on developing energy-efficient public buildings.</p>
<p>The building has a central corridor that acts as a light well over five floors, to reduce the need for artificial lighting. It also helps to reduce electricity usage, serving as warm greenhouse in winter and a source of ventilation in summer. The corridor uses an automatic system that turns lights on and off in the building’s classrooms based on students’ movement. Dong had plans, too, for a retractable shading system for the building’s facade, to control the amount of sunlight warming the building.</p>
<p>Technologies that have successfully helped buildings in the West have a lower carbon footprint won&#8217;t necessarily have the same effect in China (Credit: Reuters/Thomas Peter)<br />
Technologies that have successfully helped buildings in the West have a lower carbon footprint won&#8217;t necessarily have the same effect in China (Credit: Reuters/Thomas Peter)</p>
<p>It was an ambitious project, and Dong’s final touches didn’t make it through to completion as the university believed the retractable shade would be too complicated to build. To this day, Dong regrets not attempting the shading system. “Our calculation showed that the shade could reduce the air conditioning usage for cooling by more than one month each year,” she says.</p>
<p>Such resistance is something that resonates with others wrestling to realise their green solutions. “Refusal to try something different” is one challenge Malaysia’s Yeang points out when asked about his experience doing business in China. The 3D-printing entrepreneur Ma Yihe says he too has encountered similar issues when negotiating with traditional architectural companies.</p>
<p>Many truly passive designs, which use no fuel for heating or cooling, already exist in China’s traditional houses<br />
The slow acceptance of novelty can be a challenge, but in other respects it might also be an advantage. China’s energy consumption per building unit is still much lower than countries in the West, says Tsinghua University’s Zhu Yingxin. The difference is down to cultural and behavioural differences, she says, such as a preference for natural ventilation and a tendency to use moderate rather than icy AC.</p>
<p>Given this preference for low-energy means of temperature control, if those working in China’s building sector simply copy the west’s energy-saving practices – which usually mean a tighter mechanical control of the indoor environment – it would lead to an unnecessary rise in energy consumption instead, Zhu says. To practice green architecture in China, technologies need to be designed that best suit the local conditions, she adds, from climate to culture.</p>
<p>Many truly passive designs, which use no fuel for heating or cooling, already exist in China’s traditional houses. There are the thick-walled cave dwellings (Yaodong) on the Loess Plateau in China’s north, and the ancient Huizhou courtyards in the south. These courtyards help to regulate temperature via the stack effect, in which warm air rises through a tall space and draws a draught of cooler air in below.</p>
<p>Traditional courtyards with a central well can help regulate temperatures without using mechanical means (Credit: Alamy)<br />
Traditional courtyards with a central well can help regulate temperatures without using mechanical means (Credit: Alamy)</p>
<p>Architects can use modern technologies to further improve such designs, says Zhu, such as adding ceiling windows to a courtyard to trap heat in winter – the same principle that Dong used in her glass-ceilinged corridor design. Sometimes, even with all the benefits of modern technology and innovative architecture, the designs of the past have all the inspiration you need.</p>
<p>Zhu is optimistic about the sustainable development of urban architecture in China, which she says has been one of the key areas promoted by the government and the industry. As of the end of 2018, China had more than 10,000 architectural projects certified as “green”. A three-star rating system uses a checklist to assign points to buildings based on their land, energy, water and materials savings, as well as the building’s indoor environment quality, among other features.</p>
<p>It’s not a foolproof system, Zhu notes, as most of these certificates are only based on building design, rather than how the building actually performs in the real world – but it can be seen as indicative of a trend. In 2017, China set a goal to have 50% of all its new urban buildings certified as green by the end of 2020.</p>
<p>The rate of urban development in China is fast, but so too can be the pace of change. If half the world’s construction is indeed to happen here this decade, then raising the bar for sustainability could have an outsized impact on emissions from the built environment worldwide.</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>The emissions from travel it took to report this story were 0kg CO2: the writer interviewed sources remotely. Find out more about how we calculated this figure here.</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>Join one million Future fans by liking us on Facebook, </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/2020/04/21/uefa-recommended-to-finish-the-national-championships-and-cups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lives Matter protests: Why are statues so powerful?</title>
		<link>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/2020/04/21/croatia-met-the-national-team-after-the-final-of-the-2018-world-cup/</link>
					<comments>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/2020/04/21/croatia-met-the-national-team-after-the-final-of-the-2018-world-cup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://l91tr.yilorp.space/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After statues around the world were defaced as part of the Black Lives Matters protests, Kelly Grovier looks at why some monuments provoke powerful reactions. W What are statues for? The recent destruction of monuments in Britain and the US – from the toppling in Bristol, England, last weekend of a bronze sculpture commemorating the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After statues around the world were defaced as part of the Black Lives Matters protests, Kelly Grovier looks at why some monuments provoke powerful reactions.<br />
W<br />
What are statues for? The recent destruction of monuments in Britain and the US – from the toppling in Bristol, England, last weekend of a bronze sculpture commemorating the 18th-Century British slave trader Edward Colston, to the defacement this week in Boston, Miami and Virginia of statues venerating Christopher Columbus and Confederate leaders – raises intriguing questions about the very purpose of public statuary. Why are we compelled to create such likenesses in the first place?</p>
<p>More like this:<br />
&#8211; How Britain is facing up to its hidden slavery history<br />
&#8211; The iconic civil rights photos that still resonate<br />
&#8211; The powerful images of Hong Kong’s protests</p>
<p>The defacements in the US and the de-pedestaling of Colston, whose effigy was roughly rolled through the city streets by Black Lives Matter supporters before being dumped in a harbour, comes in the wake of the murder last month in Minneapolis, Minnesota, of an African-American, George Floyd, by a white police officer, who killed Floyd by kneeling on his neck. Floyd’s slow eight-minute asphyxiation, captured on video by a passerby, has prompted passionate protests across the world and has added fresh urgency to campaigns demanding the removal of statues that glorify figures whose reputations (and fortunes) were built on the crushing of peoples of colour and the stifling of indigenous cultures.</p>
<p>Protesters tore down a statue of Edward Colston and threw it into Bristol harbour during a Black Lives Matter rally (Credit: PA Wire)<br />
Protesters tore down a statue of Edward Colston and threw it into Bristol harbour during a Black Lives Matter rally (Credit: PA Wire)</p>
<p>In recent years, several monuments in the US that commemorate military and political leaders of the defeated southern Confederacy (which fought to preserve slavery in the 1860s) have been dismantled or relocated, whisked away from public view. The fall of Colston in Britain is part of a fresh wave of expeditious extractions washing across the West. Earlier this week, Columbus was not only beheaded in Boston but torn down by ropes both in Minneapolis, Minnesota, and in Richmond, Virginia, where the 15th-Century explorer’s effigy was dragged to a nearby pond and drowned, Colston-style. A makeshift tombstone that read ‘Racism, you will not be missed’ was placed at the water’s edge.</p>
<p>A statue of Christopher Columbus in Boston was decapitated this week; its head was later recovered by the police (Credit: Getty Images)<br />
A statue of Christopher Columbus in Boston was decapitated this week; its head was later recovered by the police (Credit: Getty Images)</p>
<p>Fearing the acceleration of similar purgings in the UK, leaders across the political spectrum raced to denounce the destruction of Colston’s statue and to caution against the ripping down of any others. In a rare instance of synchronised messaging, the UK’s Conservative Home Secretary Priti Patel and the leader of the opposition, Labour’s Sir Keir Starmer, agreed that the attacks should be condemned, as thousands gathered in Oxford to demand the removal from Oriel College of a stone statue of Cecil Rhodes, a British supremacist who enriched himself by exploiting Africa’s people and resources. At the time of writing, Rhodes’ statue, which stares through a protective mesh like a captured beast, still teeters in the balance – inviting the world to reflect on what the appropriate fate for such relics of imperial plunder ought to be.</p>
<p>The Venus of Hohle Fels is made of mammoth ivory and is the earliest known example of a depiction of a human being in prehistoric art (Credit: Alamy)<br />
The Venus of Hohle Fels is made of mammoth ivory and is the earliest known example of a depiction of a human being in prehistoric art (Credit: Alamy)</p>
<p>To answer that question, perhaps it’s worth considering why statues exist in the first place and how we are hardwired to connect with them. The earliest-known material likeness of a human being, a small statuette of a female body discovered in a cave in Germany’s Swabian Forest in 2008, may offer clues about the essence of our impulse to create such things. A mere 6cm (2.4in) in height and carved from woolly mammoth tusk 40,000 years ago, the so-called Venus of the Hohle Fels crudely exaggerates the features of a woman’s body and is thought to have served as a fertility totem.</p>
<p>From their earliest inception, statues were less about the individuals they depict than about how we see ourselves<br />
But it is not what the figurine, which demanded hundreds of hours of patient scraping to carve, depicts that is ultimately so revealing, but what it neglects to portray. The prehistoric craftsman who slowly sculpted this hunk of ivory into shape made the extraordinary aesthetic decision to leave the object without a head. Where the neck should be, a small eye-hook loop, through which a string or strip of leather could be threaded, has been painstakingly sculpted. Dangling from a necklace, the statue’s head is that of its wearer, who imaginatively completes the figurine by merging with it. From their earliest inception, in other words, statues were as much conceptual as they were material – less about the individuals they depict than about how we see ourselves.</p>
<p>Just how engrained that instinct is – to perceive an aspect of oneself in the image of another – is impossible to measure. Such an impulse may explain why it is so agonisingly difficult to tolerate the persistence of memorials that venerate past masters of pain. Theirs is a suffocating weight. The outrage that many feel about having to share the streets with such hulking ghosts of oppression is deep and crushingly real. To address the thorny issue of how best to handle monuments whose aura an appreciable proportion of society finds toxic, countries have begun to adopt a variety of different strategies.</p>
<p>The statue of merchant slave owner Robert Milligan was covered by Black Lives Matter activists in London; it was later removed by the Canal and River Trust (Credit: Getty Images)<br />
The statue of merchant slave owner Robert Milligan was covered by Black Lives Matter activists in London; it was later removed by the Canal and River Trust (Credit: Getty Images)</p>
<p>In London, the capital’s mayor, Sadiq Khan, has announced the convening of a special commission to debate the dismantling (and erection) of the city’s statues. In the US on Wednesday, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, Nancy Pelosi, hoping to pre-empt a violent plundering of Capitol Hill, called for the swift removal of 11 statues that commemorate Confederate leaders. “The statues in the Capitol should embody our highest ideals as Americans, expressing who we are and who we aspire to be as a nation,” said the California Democrat in a statement, explaining her decision. “Monuments to men who advocated cruelty and barbarism to achieve such a plainly racist end are a grotesque affront to these ideals. Their statues pay homage to hate, not heritage. They must be removed.”</p>
<p>British street artist Banksy came up with a proposal for what to do with the statue of Colston (Credit: Instagram)<br />
British street artist Banksy came up with a proposal for what to do with the statue of Colston (Credit: Instagram)</p>
<p>Is amputation the best cure for this disease? The problem, of course, in submerging mementos of a painful past in the nearest body of water is things, especially painful things, have a tendency to re-emerge from the murky deep. The British street artist Banksy, whose own work routinely dredges the shallows of society’s intolerance and forces us to confront uncomfortable shapes of hypocrisy and inequality, proposed this week an ingenious solution to the quandary that society finds itself in. “What should we do with the empty plinth in the middle of Bristol?”, Banksy asked in a post on his Instagram account. “Here’s an idea that caters for both those who miss the Colston statue and those who don’t. We drag him out the water, put him back on the plinth, tie cable round his neck and commission some life size bronze statues of protestors in the act of pulling him down. Everyone happy. A famous day commemorated.”</p>
<p>As Banksy’s accompanying drawing (which wittily imagines a precariously repositioned Colston, faltering forever on the verge of collapse) suggests, what’s tricky is finding the right balance when ‘catering’ to the diverging perspectives of everyone in society who must bear the weight of a statue. In Germany, where decisions long ago had to be taken about how the Nazi era would be fossilised in the material memory of the nation’s streets and squares, it was resolved that erasing the past was not an option. Rather than polluting the municipal air with monuments to the perpetrators of pain, however, efforts have been made to preserve instead memorials that honour the fortitude of Hitler’s victims. Perhaps we should think of statues the way we think of trees. When one is found to be disfigured by disease we should resolve to plant a fresh copse, one that cleanses the atmosphere and doesn’t choke our breath.</p>
<p>If you would like to comment on this story or anything else you have seen on BBC Culture, head over to our Facebook page or message us on Twitter.</p>
<p>And if you liked this story, sign up for the weekly bbc.com features newsletter, called The Essential List. A handpicked selection of stories from BBC Future, Culture, Worklife and Travel, delivered to your inbox every Friday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/2020/04/21/croatia-met-the-national-team-after-the-final-of-the-2018-world-cup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>George Floyd: Trump told to back off Seattle&#8217;s Chaz police-free zone</title>
		<link>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/2020/04/21/startup_ukr/</link>
					<comments>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/2020/04/21/startup_ukr/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 16:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://l91tr.yilorp.space/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State authorities in the north-western US state of Washington have hit back after President Donald Trump threatened to &#8220;take back&#8221; a police-free district controlled by protesters in Seattle. Governor Jay Inslee said Mr Trump should stay out of the state&#8217;s business, and Seattle&#8217;s mayor said any invasion of the city would be illegal. Police abandoned [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>State authorities in the north-western US state of Washington have hit back after President Donald Trump threatened to &#8220;take back&#8221; a police-free district controlled by protesters in Seattle.</p>
<p>Governor Jay Inslee said Mr Trump should stay out of the state&#8217;s business, and Seattle&#8217;s mayor said any invasion of the city would be illegal.</p>
<p>Police abandoned a precinct there on Monday after days of clashes.</p>
<p>Mr Trump said the area had been overtaken by &#8220;domestic terrorists&#8221;.</p>
<p>Since police withdrew, demonstrations in the area have been largely peaceful.</p>
<p>It has been called Chaz, an abbreviation of Capitol Hill Autonomous Zone. Hundreds of people have been gathering there to demonstrate, hear speeches and attend events.</p>
<p>Is Trump in trouble for his stance on race?<br />
US military chief sorry for joining Trump walk<br />
Seven solutions to US police problems<br />
The protests in Seattle, Washington began in response to last month&#8217;s death in police custody of an unarmed black man, George Floyd, in Minneapolis, Minnesota.</p>
<p>President Trump, who has pushed states to take firm action against protesters, has meanwhile outlined proposals for reforming police, including greater funding for training and national guidelines on the use of force.</p>
<p>However, he dismissed calls for defunding the police as an &#8220;extreme agenda&#8221;. Such a measure involves budgets being allocated directly to communities rather than law enforcement.</p>
<p>Image copyrightAFP<br />
Image caption<br />
Hundreds of protesters have gathered in the Chaz<br />
How did the &#8216;Chaz&#8217; come about?<br />
The area around East Precinct in Seattle became a battleground between protesters and police in the past two weeks, leading the governor to send in the National Guard and for the mayor to impose a curfew.</p>
<p>During the violence, demonstrators threw missiles at police, cars were torched and looting broke out, according to local media.</p>
<p>At the weekend, Seattle police used tear gas and flash bangs to disperse protesters. Members of the city council rebuked the police department, accusing them of heavy-handed tactics.</p>
<p>Then on Monday, the mayor ordered barricades removed near the precinct and the police building was boarded up.</p>
<p>Since then protesters have taken over a zone spanning about six blocks of Capitol Hill, a hub of the city&#8217;s trendy arts scene that has been gentrified in recent years as tech workers drive up property prices.</p>
<p>Image copyrightAFP<br />
Image caption<br />
Protesters have hung a sign over the Seattle Police Department&#8217;s now-closed East Precinct<br />
What do the protesters want?<br />
Their demands include &#8220;defunding&#8221; the police &#8211; reducing funding to spend more on health and other community services &#8211; better disciplinary policies for police and the dropping of criminal charges against protesters.</p>
<p>&#8220;My grandparents marched and they were scared of getting dogs on them and tear gas,&#8221; said 15-year-old protester Francis Vann, quoted by the Seattle Times newspaper.</p>
<p>&#8220;Tear gas isn&#8217;t going to hurt me, isn&#8217;t going to stop me. I&#8217;m young. I just really want a change.&#8221;</p>
<p>Local media describe a festival-like atmosphere, with poetry readings, music and movie nights. Free fizzy water, snacks, sunscreen and hand sanitiser are available.</p>
<p>While the protesters say they are leaderless, armed volunteers have been spotted at checkpoints asking for the ID of people entering.</p>
<p>What did Trump say about Chaz?<br />
In a series of tweets, the Republican president lashed out at liberal Democratic leaders in the north-western US state of Washington and its most populous city of Seattle.</p>
<p>&#8220;Take back your city NOW,&#8221; Mr Trump wrote on Thursday. &#8220;If you don&#8217;t do it, I will.&#8221;</p>
<p>Image copyrightAFP<br />
Image caption<br />
Protesters in the Chaz have created a memorial of George Floyd and others<br />
In another tweet, he said &#8220;Domestic Terrorists have taken over Seattle&#8221;, saying Washington Governor Jay Inslee was &#8220;looking &#8216;the fool'&#8221;.</p>
<p>Mr Inslee tweeted back: &#8220;A man who is totally incapable of governing should stay out of Washington state&#8217;s business.&#8221;</p>
<p>Seattle Mayor Jenny Durkan defended the right to protest and told President Trump: &#8220;Make us all safe. Go back to your bunker.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The threat to invade Seattle, to divide and incite violence in our city, is not only unwelcome, it would be illegal,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>Could the president carry out his threat?<br />
Earlier this month, when protests were spreading across the US, Mr Trump threatened to send in the US Army if state governors &#8211; who oversee law and order &#8211; were unable to guarantee safety and secure property on their streets.</p>
<p>Media caption&#8221;Keep pushing&#8221;: Washington DC protesters on keeping the momentum going<br />
This would involve invoking the Insurrection Act, a 19th Century law which includes details of circumstances when the government in Washington DC can intervene without state authorisation.</p>
<p>Trump threatens to send in army<br />
Can President Trump deploy the military?<br />
Trump to restart rallies on key slavery date<br />
The act says the approval of governors is not required when the president determines the situation in a state makes it impossible to enforce US laws, or when citizens&#8217; rights are threatened.</p>
<p>This law was last invoked in 1992 during riots in Los Angeles following the acquittal of four police officers charged with assaulting black motorist Rodney King, but on that occasion the governor of California requested help.</p>
<p>The law was used throughout the 1950s and 60s during the civil rights era by three different presidents. On some of these occasions there were objections from state governors.</p>
<p>How do police see it?<br />
Police say they want to reopen the precinct and it is unclear how long the autonomous zone will remain.</p>
<p>At a news conference on Wednesday, Assistant Chief Deanna Nollette said the police department had been abandoned because of threats that it would be vandalised or burned. She said the protesters&#8217; barricades were intimidating some residents.</p>
<p>Police Chief Carmen Best posted a video message to officers in which she said the police withdrawal &#8220;seems like an insult to you and our community&#8221;.</p>
<p>On Thursday afternoon the police chief said claims that citizens and businesses were being extorted in the zone were not true and had been based on anecdotal evidence from news and social media.</p>
<p>Image copyrightAFP<br />
Image caption<br />
Artists painted the words &#8216;Black Lives Matters&#8217; on a street in the Chaz<br />
Ms Best said call response times in the area served by East Precinct are normally between 5-18 minutes, but are now taking almost an hour, reports local Komo News.</p>
<p>She said this means police are not able to respond to reports of assaults, rapes and robberies.</p>
<p>More on George Floyd&#8217;s death<br />
VIEWPOINT: Tipping point for racially divided nation<br />
WATCH: &#8216;This is why we are protesti</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://l91tr.yilorp.space/w.php/2020/04/21/startup_ukr/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
